Guide to the New England Church Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Connecticut Churches, Series I
  - Winsted
    - Second Congregational Church, 1883-1899 (Box 35)
    - Second Congregational Church, 1900-1912 (Box 21)
  - Wolcottvile
    - Congregational Church, 1876 (Box 55)
  - Woodbridge
    - First Church of Christ Congregational, 1915, 1916, 1963 (Box 21)
  - Woodbury
    - First Congregational Church, 1870, 1870, 1889 (Box 34)
    - Methodist Church, 1940 (Box 21)
  - Woodstock
    - First Congregational Church, 1940, n.d. (Box 34)
- Maine Churches, Series II
  - Augusta
    - South Parish Congregational Church, 1944 (Box 36)
  - Bangor
    - Central Congregational Church, 1857 (Box 36)
    - First Congregational Church, 1856 (Box 36)
    - Hammond Street Church, 1908, 1912 (Box 36)
  - Bath
    - First Congregational Church, 1836 (Box 36)
    - Winter Street Church, 1863, 1895 (Box 22)
  - Belfast
    - First Congregational Church, 1831, 1843 (Box 36)
  - Biddeford
    - Pavilion Church, 1884 (Box 36)
  - Brunswick
    - First Congregational Church, 1872, 1909 (Box 36)
  - Buxton
    - Church of Christ, 1868 (Box 22)
  - Cape Elizabeth
    - First Congregational Church, 1907, 1909 (Box 36)
  - East Brewer
    - Congregational Church, 1835 (Box 36)
  - Gardiner
    - Congregational Church, 1885 (Box 36)
  - Gorham
    - Congregational Church, 1849, 1879, 1886 (Box 36)
  - Harpswell
    - Congregational Church, 1903 (Box 54)
  - Kennebunk
    - Baptist Church, 1833 (Box 50)
  - Lebanon
    - Congregational Church, 1903 (Box 54)
  - Lewiston
    - Pine Street Congregational Church, 1863-1879 (Box 36)
  - Portland
    - Episcopal Church, 1863 (Box 36)
    - High Street Congregational Church, 1855 (Box 36)
    - St. Luke's Cathedral, 1881 (Box 51)
    - State Street Church, 1856, 1904 (Box 22)
    - Third Congregational Church, 1865 (Box 22)
    - Williston Church, 1893 (Box 22)
  - Sacarappa
    - Congregational Church, 1879 (Box 54)
  - Saco
    - First Church, 1862 (Box 54)
  - Scarboro
    - Scarboro Church, 1879 (Box 54)
  - Thomaston
    - Church of St. John the Baptist, 1934 (Box 22)
  - Waldoboro
    - First Congregational Church, 1858 (Box 36)
  - Waterford
    - First Congregational Church, 1885 (Box 36)
  - Westbrook
    - Second Church Westbrook, 1879 (Box 54)
  - Wiscasset
    - First Congregational Church, 1909 (Box 36)
- Massachusetts Churches, Series III
  - Amherst
    - Church of Christ in Amherst College, 1878 (Box 37)
  - Andover
    - Christ Church, 1886 (Box 48)
    - Free Christian Church, 1856 (Box 37)
    - West Church and Parish, 1926 (Box 37)
  - Arlington
    - Orthodox Congregational Church, 1902 (Box 37)
  - Ashfield
    - Congregational Church, 1855 (Box 49)
    - First Congregational Church, 1895 (Box 54)
  - Athol
    - Church in Evangelical Society, 1831 (Box 37)
  - Attleborough
    - Second Congregational Church, 1838 (Box 22)
  - Auburndale
    - Congregational Church, 1844, 1868 (Box 37)
  - Boston
    - Appleton Street Church, 1884-1889 (Box 22)
    - Arlington Street Church, 1867 (Box 22)
    - Belknap Street Sabbath School, 1836 (Box 22)
    - Berkeley Street Church, 1889 (Box 22)
    - Berkeley Temple, 1890 (Box 22)
    - Boylston Congregational Church, 1903-1905 (Box 42)
    - Brattle Square Church (also known as Brattle Street Church), 1847, n.d. (Box 22)
    - Central Church, 1869 (Box 22)
    - Central Congregational Church, 1908-1909 (Box 54)
    - Chambers Street Chapel, 1863, 1866 (Box 22)
    - Christ Church, 1823, 1855, 1874, 1913, 1933, 1944 (Box 22)
    - Church of the Advent, 1855, 1855, 1861-1878 (Box 22)
    - Emmanuel Church, 1861 (Box 55)
    - Essex Street Church, 1823, 1866 (Box 37)
    - First Church of Christ, 1880, 1909 (Box 22)
    - Hollis Street Church, 1839-1879 (Box 22, Box 50)
    - King's Chapel, 1886, 1910 1976 (Box 23)
    - Mason Street Sabbath School, 1839 (Box 50)
    - Morgan Memorial, 1859 (Box 23)
    - New North Church, 1814, 1849 (Box 42)
    - New South Free Church and Society, 1881 (Box 42)
    - New Tremont Temple, n.d. (Box 51)
    - Old South Church, 1845-1909, 1945, n.d. (Box 37)
    - Park Street Church, 1825-1910, 1962 (Box 23)
    - Payson Church, 1846 (Box 23)
    - [Dorcester District] Pilgrim Church, 1898 (Box 55)
    - Purchase Street Congregational Church, 1840 (Box 23)
    - St. Paul's Church, 1820, n.d., 1846, 1846, 1846, 1847, 1875-1918 (Box 23)
    - Trinity Church: General, 1845-1872, 1952, n.d. (Box 23)
    - Trinity Church: Calendar/ News, 1910-1929 (Box 41)
    - Trinity Church: Calendar/ News, 1923-1929 (Box 42)
    - Union Church, 1830, 1911, n.d. (Box 23)
    - Union Congregational Church, 1907, 1912 (Box 54)
    - Warren Street Chapel, 1837-1892 (Box 28)
    - Winthrop Congregational Church, 1895-1896 (Box 37)
  - Boxford
    - First Congregational Church, 1900 (Box 37)
  - Bradford
    - First Church of Christ, 1832 (Box 23)
  - Braintree
    - First Congregational Church, 1861 (Box 23)
  - Brimfield
    - First Congregational Church (see also RG 44, #31), 1856, 1940 (Box 37)
  - Brockton
    - First Congregational Church, 1885 (Box 54)
    - Porter Church, 1899 (Box 23)
    - South Congregational Church, 1915 (Box 23)
  - Brookfield
    - Congregational Church, 1832 (Box 23)
    - First Church, 1867 (Box 23)
  - Brookline
    - Church of Our Savior, 1919-1921 (Box 40)
    - Harvard Church, 1944 (Box 23)
  - Cambridge
    - First Church of Christ, 1886, 1907 (Box 23)
    - North Avenue Baptist Church, 1894, 1930 (Box 54)
    - North Avenue Congregational Church, 1880 (Box 50)
    - Prospect Street Church, 1895 (Box 23)
    - St. James's Episcopal Church, 1945 (Box 23)
  - Cambridgeport
    - First Evangelical Congregational Church, 1857 (Box 39)
    - Pilgrim Congregational Church, 1885, 1887 (Box 39)
    - Second Evangelical Congregational Church, 1843 (Box 39)
  - Charlestown
    - First Church, 1882 (Box 38)
    - Harvard Church, 1879 (Box 23)
    - St. John's Church, 1939, 1940 (Box 23)
  - Chelmsford
    - Church of Christ, n.d. (Box 38)
  - Chelsea
    - Broadway Church, 1859 (Box 38)
  - Chicopee
    - Third Congregational Sunday-school (Box 50)
  - Danvers
    - First Church, 1879 (Box 24)
  - Danvers Highlands
    - First Church, 1910-1912 (Box 24)
  - Dedham
    - First Congregational Church, 1877 (Box 24)
  - Deerfield
    - First Church, 1857 (Box 54)
  - Dorchester
    - Second Church, 1812, 1873, 1883 (Box 24)
    - Second Congregational Church (Box 54)
    - Bethany Congregational Church, 1888 (Box 54)
    - Central Congregational Church, No date (Box 55)
  - Dudley
    - Congregational Church, 1845 (Box 24)
  - Easthampton
    - First Church, 1878 (Box 24)
    - St. Philip's Episcopal Church, 1946 (Box 49)
  - Easton
    - Evangelical Congregational Church, 1888 (Box 54)
  - Fall River
    - First Congregational Church, 1909 (Box 54)
  - Globe Village
    - Evangelical Free Church, 1891 (Box 55)
  - Goshen
    - Church of Goshen, 1824 (Box 38)
  - Granville
    - First Church of Christ, 1895 (Box 24)
  - Great Barrington
    - First Congregational Church, 1941 (Box 38)
  - Greenfield
    - Second Congregational Church, 1858 (Box 38)
  - Groton
    - First Church, 1872 (Box 24)
    - First Parish of Groton, 1896-1908 (Box 49)
    - Union Congregational Church, 1888-1915 (Box 24)
  - Harvard
    - Evangelical Congregational Church, 1866 (Box 24)
  - Haverhill
    - Center Church, 1883 (Box 24)
  - Holliston
    - First Congregational Church, 1852, 1879 (Box 38)
  - Holyoke
    - Second Baptist Church, 1890 (Box 24)
    - Second Congregational Church, 1886 (Box 24)
    - Skinner Memorial Chapel, 1918 (Box 49)
  - Hyde Park
    - Clarendon Congregational Church, 1891 (Box 55)
    - First Congregational Church, 1888 (Box 24)
  - Lancaster
    - First Church, 1917 (Box 23)
  - Leicester
    - Congregational Church, 1823 (Box 38)
  - Lenox
    - Trinity Church, 1901, 1918 (Box 24)
  - Lexington
    - First Congregational Church, 1904 (Box 50)
  - Littleton
    - Orthodox Congregational Church, 1940 (Box 38)
  - Ludlow
    - First Congregational Church, 1857 (Box 50)
  - Lowell
    - First Congregational Church, 1858, 1896 (Box 38)
    - High Street Church, 1896 (Box 38)
    - Kirk Street Church, 1899 (Box 38)
    - Second Universalist Church, 1870 (Box 54)
  - Malden
    - Maplewood Congregational Church, 1901 (Box 23)
  - Manchester
    - Orthodox Congregational Church, 1851 (Box 23)
  - Marblehead
    - St. Michael's Church, 1888 (Box 24)
  - Marshfield
    - First Baptist Church, 1888 (Box 24)
  - Maynard
    - Evangelical Union Church, 1878 (Box 54)
  - Medford
    - The Mystic Church, 1848 (Box 38)
  - Monson
    - Congregational Church (see also: Brimfield), 1875 (Box 51)
  - Nantucket
    - First Congregational Church, 1970 (Box 48)
  - Nashua
    - Olive Street Church, 1858 (Box 23)
  - Newton
    - Channing Church, 1882, 1901 (Box 23)
    - First Church, 1876, 1895, 1914 (Box 23)
  - North Abington
    - Congregational Church, n.d. (Box 54)
  - North Wrentham
    - The Church in North Wrentham, 1825 (Box 24)
  - Northampton
    - First Congregational Church, n.d. (Box 38)
  - Northborough
    - Evangelical Congregational Church, 1882 (Box 24)
  - Northbridge
    - Congregational Church, 1867 (Box 23)
  - Oakham
    - Congregational Church, 1862 (Box 38)
  - Paxton
    - Congregational Church, 1873 (Box 43)
  - Peabody
    - South Church, 1913 (Box 43)
  - Plymouth
    - First Church, 1893 (Box 54)
    - Second Church (Congregational), 1938 (Box 54)
    - Third Congregational Church, 1839 (Box 43)
  - Provincetown
    - Church of the Redeemer, Universalist, 1922 (Box 43)
  - Quincy
    - Bethany Church, 1903 (Box 54)
    - Christ Church, 1915 (Box 24)
    - Evangelical Congregational Church, 1857 (Box 54)
  - Reading
    - First Church, 1825, 1838 (Box 51)
    - First Parish, 1914 (Box 24)
  - Rockland
    - First Congregational Church, 1913 (Box 24)
  - Rockport
    - Second Orthodox Congregational Church, 1855 (Box 24)
  - Roxbury
    - Walnut Avenue Congregational Church, 1896 (Box 43)
    - First Church, n.d. (Box 54)
  - Salem
    - Crombie Street Church, 1853-1884 (Box 24)
    - First Church, 1871, 1897 (Box 24)
    - Independent Cong. Church, 1825 (Box 24)
    - Tabernacle Church, 1854, 1855, 1863 (Box 24)
  - Scituate
    - First Trinity Congregational Church of Christ, 1853 (Box 43)
  - Sharon
    - Congregational Church, n.d. (Box 55)
  - South Boston
    - Hawes Place Society, 1844 (Box 50)
  - South Deerfield
    - Monument Church, 1859 (Box 54)
  - South Framington
    - South Congregational Church, 1886 (Box 43)
  - South Groton
    - South Groton Christian Union Meetinghouse, 1855 (Box 43)
  - South Hadley
    - First Congregational Church, 1861, 1866, n.d. (Box 49)
  - South Hadley Falls
    - Congregational Church, 1867 (Box 43)
  - Springfield
    - Christ Church, 1900 (Box 43)
    - Christ Church Cathedral, 1937 (Box 43)
    - First Church of Christ, 1879, 1887 (Box 43)
    - Hope Congregational Church, 1901 (Box 43)
    - North Church, 1889 (Box 54)
    - North Congregational Church, n.d. (Box 54)
    - St. John's Congregational Church, 1929, no date (Box 43)
    - St. Paul's Church, 1870 (Box 43)
    - South Congregational Church, 1873-1875 (Box 24)
  - Stockbridge
    - Congregational Church, 1853 (Box 38)
  - Sutton
    - First Congregational Church, 1790, 1871, 1891, 1904 (Box 38)
  - Taunton
    - Union Congregational Church, 1893 (Box 38)
  - Topsfield
    - Congregational Church, 1909 (Box 38)
  - Wakefield
    - Congregational Church, 1882 (Box 24)
  - Waltham
    - Trinitarian Congregational Church, 1860 (Box 38)
  - Ware Village
    - Congregational Church, 1843 (Box 24)
  - Watertown
    - First Congregational Church, 1942 (Box 43)
  - Wellesley Hills
    - First Congregational Church, n.d. (Box 49)
  - West Barnstable
    - Congregational Church, 1916 (Box 24)
  - West Springfield
    - First Congregational Church, 1824, 1884 (Box 24)
  - Westborough
    - Evangelical Church, 1890 (Box 54)
  - Westfield
    - Second Congregational Church, 1906 (Box 43)
  - Westhampton
    - Congregational Church, 1979-1980 (Box 24)
  - Weymouth
    - Union Church and Religious Society, 1857 (Box 24)
    - First Congregational Church, 1888 (Box 54)
  - Whitinsville
    - Village Congregational Church, 1917 (Box 38)
  - Wilmington
    - First Church of Christ, 1885 (Box 43)
  - Winchendon
    - North Congregational Church, 1873 (Box 55)
  - Worcester
    - All Saints' Parish, 1894 (Box 43)
    - Calvinist Church, 1878 (Box 54)
    - Central Congregational Church, 1889 (Box 49)
    - First Church, 1820, 1821, 1821, 1861, 1916 (Box 38)
    - Old South Meeting House, 1863 (Box 55)
    - Piedmont Church, 1881 (Box 38)
    - Plymouth Congregational Church, 1884 (Box 54)
    - St. John's Church, 1888, 1897-1899 (Box 43)
    - Second Congregational Church, 1829 (Box 55)
    - Union Church, 1886, 1881-1883 (Box 38)
  - Yarmouth
    - Congregational Church, 1873 (Box 43)
- New Hampshire Churches, Series IV
  - Boscawen
    - First Church, 1864 (Box 39)
    - Second Congregational Church, 1838 (Box 51)
  - Brentwood
    - Congregational Church (Annals), 1889 (Box 54)
  - Claremont
    - Trinity Parish, 1864 (Box 39)
  - Concord
    - First Congregational Church, 1830, 1888 (Box 39)
  - Dover
    - Belknap Church, 1861 (Box 39)
  - Exeter
    - Philips Church, 1906 (Box 39)
  - Greenland
    - Methodist Episcopal Church, 1909
  - Hanover
    - Church of Christ at Dartmouth, 1855, 1935 (Box 25)
  - Keene
    - Baptist Church, 1886 (Box 39)
  - Manchester
    - Grace Church, 1941 (Box 49)
  - Mount Vernon
    - Congregational Church, 1880-1885 (Box 39)
  - New-Durham
    - Church of Christ, 1811 (Box 39)
  - Plainfield
    - Congregational Church of Christ, n.d. (Box 39)
  - Portsmouth
    - North Church, 1854 (Box 39)
    - St. John's Church, 1947 (Box 39)
    - South Parish Sunday School, 1840 (Box 54)
  - Salmon Falls
    - Congregational Church, 1852 (Box 25)
  - Sanbornton
    - First Baptist Church, 1833 (Box 51)
  - Wilton
    - Second Congregational Church, 1875 (Box 55)
  - Windham
    - Presbyterian Church, 1839 (copy) (Box 25)
- Rhode Island Churches, Series V
  - Little Compton
    - United Congregational Church, 1880, 1904 (Box 39)
  - Narragansett
    - Peace Dale Church, 1895 (Box 39)
  - Newport
    - Second Baptist Church, 1656-1936 (Box 49)
    - Shiloh Baptist Church, 1901 (Box 39)
    - United Congregational, 1914 (Box 39)
  - Providence
    - Beneficient Congregational Church, 1893 (Box 54)
    - First Congregational Church, 1910, n.d. (Box 39)
    - First Universalist Society, 1831 (Box 50)
    - Grace Church, 1898 (Box 54)
    - Pilgrim Congregational Church, 1889 (Box 39)
    - Westminster Church, 1856 (Box 50)
  - Westerly
    - Christ Church, 1869 (Box 25)
- Vermont Churches, Series VI
  - Bennington
    - Congregational Church, 1923, 1935 (Box 25)
  - Bradford
    - Congregational Church, 1859 (Box 39)
  - Burlington
    - College Street Congregational Church, 1900-1904 (Box 42)
    - White Street Congregational Church, 1867 (Box 49)
  - Jericho
    - First Congregational Church, 1891 (Box 39)
  - Middlebury
    - Congregational Church, 1853 (Box 39)
  - Montpelier
    - Christ Church, 1905 (Box 25)
  - New Haven
    - Congregational Church, 1836 (Box 39)
  - Newbury
    - Congregational Church, 1858 (Box 39)
  - Pittsford
    - Congregational Church, 1834 (Box 39)
  - Proctor
    - Union Church, 1916 (Box 39)
  - St. Johnsbury
    - South Congregational Church, 1884, 1892, 1889 (Box 39)
  - Springfield
    - Congregational (Orthodox) Church, 1842 (Box 39)
  - Vergennes
    - Congregational Church, 1879, 1893 (Box 39)
  - West Brattleboro
    - Congregational Church, (1863?), 1887 (Box 25)
  - Windsor
    - Congregational Church, 1889 (Box 25)
  - Woodstock
    - First Congregational Church, 1899 (Box 39)